<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Mysite]]></title><description><![CDATA[Mysite]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 06:56:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Module 6 Reflection]]></title><description><![CDATA[What technological knowledge have you learned in this course? What pedagogical knowledge (e.g., knowledge about adult learning theories,...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/module-6-reflection</link><guid isPermaLink="false">608a53909ec68700151056c5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 06:54:48 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li>What technological knowledge have you learned in this course? What pedagogical knowledge (e.g., knowledge about adult learning theories, instructional design, online learning and teaching) have you learned in this course?<ol>
  <li>I had honestly no idea how LMS really worked or what went into making a course using a LMS until I learned about them in this class. </li>
  <li>It has taken a while for me to really grasp the idea that adult learners learn differently from children. Granted, I feel as though that should have been a give, as I despise fill-in-the-blank sheets, like the ones I once completed in high school. During one of the modules of this course, I was given the opportunity to create my own lesson, but I went overboard and decided to design a mini-course. During my planning phase, Dr. Ching pointed out how I was mainly relying on students reading, and remembering, and then doing.... worksheets. The very thing I do not enjoy. I pondered how to go about teaching a concept that doesn't have any form of binary wrong or write answers, and with input from Dr. Ching, I decided to rely heavily on the use of discussion and creation. "Adult learners learn best from creating." Is the message that sticks out the most in my mind. Creating artifacts that pertain to the learned subject matter is the top level of learning. You analyze the information given to you and are able to create a project that reflects how you see that information within your own mind. I suppose this might have been why I enjoyed creating a course on a topic I had spent so long teaching myself about. My course was centered around teaching nonviolent communication, so using discussion boards should have been my first thought honestly. Providing the opportunity for the theoretical students I was teaching to create their own dialog, and connect the lessons to things that they experience in their daily lives.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p>2. Explain how your learning in this course will make an impact on your current or future work. Will any artifacts you created be shared with your students or colleagues?<p>a. Returning to that mini-course I made. Nonviolent Communication is a course I actually want to teach. I will need to get certified in it, but that's okay. Ultimately, I'd like to see it offered as a UF at Boise State University. I will continue to work on my version of the course and tweak it little by little as I hone in on how to teach this particular topic. Learning Design and Information Design are iterative processes, so this only being the first incarnation, kind of second, of this course means it is nowhere near its final form, and meaning its also nowhere near being ready to use as a real course. Any opportunities my future classes will give me to work on, and improve this course as a whole I will be taking advantage of. My main focus is esports, I have never thought in the traditional sense of the word at all in my life. I've honestly felt rather inadequate in comparison to some of my other peers in this field of study as I am lacking in that department.  But, if I can keep working on this one particular artifact throughout my time as a Master's student I feel like I will learn a lot about teaching, from those I will be receiving feedback from, as they are already teachers. While I don't really know how I am going to be able to apply upper levels of learning to the world of Overwatch Coaching, I am still brainstorming with my Director as to how we can have our players create something that helps them learn more in a shorter period of time. One such idea was having each player take turn doing my job of scouting teams we are going up against, and improving their abilities to spot trends, and important information, </p></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 5 Reflection]]></title><description><![CDATA[If this module I was tasked with developing an assignment and lesson for topic of my choice. I choice Nonviolent Communication as it is a...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/module-4-reflection</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6073f594e3733e001519960f</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 07:30:34 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If this module I was tasked with developing an assignment and lesson for topic of my choice. I choice Nonviolent Communication as it is a topic that is near and dear to my heart. To start out I'd like to say that when it comes to website building I am pretty well rounded. However, being kept within the bounds of BlackBoard was a frustrating experience, as it limited my creativity. Honestly, I would have love have designed a whole course site on my own, but I didn't have the time. </p>

<p>The main style I used for instruction I was a connectivism approach mixed with tradition reading instruction. I wanted student to reflect on the material through the discussion and connect that discussion post to their daily lives. My motivation for this was that everyone every day communicates to someone (hopefully), either verbally face-to-face or through electronic communications. As the course as a whole is rather short, the final assessment is a culmination of their knowledge to create an animated video of scenario that utilizes the aspects of NVC that are taught throughout the course. Reflection allows for introspection into ourselves. NVC puts a heavy focus on how we view things, internalize and interpret them, and then speak to others.  By allowing for student to reflect on their own actions, or actions they observed on TV if they did not feel comfortable sharing about themselves, allows for the reframing of their mindset that is important to NVC. </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 3 Reflection]]></title><description><![CDATA[As someone who is enticed to play a game, or a particular moment in history, by the story that is told, the idea of turning my teaching...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/module-3-reflection</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6034c2b269140b0017caa1d6</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 10:02:53 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As someone who is enticed to play a game, or a particular moment in history, by the story that is told, the idea of turning my teaching into a story is not something that I had thought of until this Module. In Game Design we discussed ways to keep the players' attention. Sometimes it's in the form of add ons, multiplayer,  or an enticing story. A good story holds the players' attention making them want to come back until they reach the end. However, in many cases of teaching the story is already written. 2 + 2  will always be four. The teacher can't change that. What the teacher can change is the way in which the material is delivered. Even in an online learning environment teachers can construct narratives to make the material we are reading more interesting. In math class, the teachers could use more student involvement while introducing new content, an example would be a song written about the square root of a quadrat Function. From what I've heard the best time to ignite someone's love of learning, math, in particular, is in middle school.  According a teacher my significant other once had. </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 1 Blog Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[Andragogy is term that means the art and science of adult learning. Andragogy relates to adult online learning, because it is a form on...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/module-1-blog-post</link><guid isPermaLink="false">600e842a7103f700173e2102</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 08:54:40 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Andragogy is term that means the art and science of adult learning. Andragogy relates to adult online learning, because it is a form on learning and teaching to adults, that also involves technology to aid in that learning. Both the teaching and learning taking place through the medium of technology. It is also a learner focused form of education.</p>

<p>The main criticism of andragogy is that, due to it's lack of teacher based evaluations using empirical data, it is hard to scientifically study how effective or ineffective this type of teaching and learning style truly is. There isn't a science to creative learning, so there isn't a science to creative teaching.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[EdTech 502 Reflection]]></title><description><![CDATA[Throughout this course, I learned about creating accessible websites that adhere to AECT guidelines. I learned how to create, and apply...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/edtech-502-reflection</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd1b52f9ca580001804dd41</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 05:50:50 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Throughout this course, I learned about creating accessible websites that adhere to AECT guidelines. I learned how to create, and apply external and internal style sheets using .css with HTML code. </p>
<p>I also learned the importance I testing if your website is truly accessible to people with different types of learning disabilities. While not all of my websites are up to a level where I can comfortably say they are 100% accessible, I am well on my way to being able to.</p>
<p>I also learned how to properly use information and graphics from outside sources while respecting copyright laws. </p>
<p>I had the opportunity to learn about website design and principles to help me create professional-looking education websites. Though I am comfortable with HTML and .css, I had limited experience creating webpages with the intent for them to be used as a source of information outside of a resume. I had never previously considered things such as layout, or color having an effect on someone's ability to utilize my webpage properly. Now, it is something always in the back of my mind when I am designing anything from a logo to a video game character.</p>
<p>Before this course, I had never had to connect my webpages to a server that wasn't my own. This was my first experience using someone else's, the school's in this case.  I'm very thankful for its stability. Though I still need some help linking my GitHub to Dreamweaver, that's not an issue I need to solve just yet.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[EdTech Definition Graphic]]></title><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/edtech-definition-graphic</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd161e18df94200179362c3</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 23:48:19 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://static.wixstatic.com/media/0c32c0_e5ddcd19ef4f4f568ffea6aab1599215~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/0c32c0_e5ddcd19ef4f4f568ffea6aab1599215~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[School Evaluation Summary Artifact]]></title><description><![CDATA[AECT - 5 - Assessing/Evaluating Candidates apply formal inquiry strategies in assessing and evaluating processes and resources for...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/school-evaluation-summary-artifact</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd161638968d90017ceb8cd</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 23:45:34 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AECT - 5 - Assessing/Evaluating</p>
<p>Candidates apply formal inquiry strategies in assessing and evaluating processes and resources for learning and performance.</p>
<p>AECT Standards, 2012 version</p>
<p>AECT Standard 5 - Research</p> ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[EdTech Research Artifact]]></title><description><![CDATA[Fall 2020 AECT - 5 - Theoretical Foundations Candidates demonstrate foundational knowledge of the contribution of research to the past...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/edtech-research-artifact</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd16068399d800017b2fcd2</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 23:41:58 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fall 2020</p>
<p>AECT - 5 - Theoretical Foundations</p>
<p>Candidates demonstrate foundational knowledge of the contribution of research to the past and current theory of educational communications and technology.</p>
<p>AECT Standard 5 - Research</p> ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Flipped Classroom Presentation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Here's is a presentation I made about the implementation of a flipped classroom model. Explaining how it would be beneficial. Semester:...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/flipped-classroom-presentation</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd15cabc135d90017095de6</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 23:35:14 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[ <p>Here's is a presentation I made about the implementation of a flipped classroom model. Explaining how it would be beneficial.</p>
<p>Semester: Fall 2020</p>
<p>AECT - 1 - Assessing/Evaluating</p>
<p>Candidates demonstrate the ability to assess and evaluate the effective integration of appropriate technologies and instructional materials.</p>
<p>AECT - 1 - Using</p>
<p>AECT Standard 1 - Content Knowledge</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[EdTech Professional Ethics Ethics Animation]]></title><description><![CDATA[https://www.powtoon.com/c/d1pOnoIdKmk/2/m Here you can find a link to a animation I created using an online software called PowToon. In...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/professional-ethics-ethics-animation</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd15bb741ea6100177d1d22</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 23:22:32 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.powtoon.com/c/d1pOnoIdKmk/2/m" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.powtoon.com/c/d1pOnoIdKmk/2/m</u></a> </p>
<p>Here you can find a link to a animation I created using an online software called PowToon. In this animation I demonstrated the application of the 4th aspect of the AECT standards.</p>
<p>Semester: Spring 2020</p>
<p>AECT - 1 - Ethics</p>
<p>Candidates demonstrate the contemporary professional ethics of the field as defined and developed by the Association for Educational Communications and Technology.</p>
<p>AECT Standard 1 - Content Knowledge</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Becoming An EdTech Innovator]]></title><description><![CDATA[Should we be teaching people how to utilize their social media for their personal and social growth? Since March 26th here in the United...]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/becoming-an-edtech-innovator</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fc99e5bbe4ba30017f5cdc1</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 03:22:41 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Should we be teaching people how to utilize their social media for their personal and social growth?</p>

<p>Since March 26th here in the United States, and elsewhere, people have had to social distance. With that in mind, think about how many missed encounters, and missed interactions you and those around you have lost. If it helps, in 2013 on average people met 3 new people every day. Assuming that we stuck with three, the average person has missed out on 756 chance encounters. </p>

<p>What we can't do is sit and stagnate, and allow the fact that we can't meet face-to-face anymore to prevent us from going forward in our lives. The answer to socializing at a distance has existed for over a decade. We just hadn't been forced to exclusively use social media to make friends. </p>

<p>With that changing, we witnessed the birth of new MemeLords, White Knights, and Karens from our own friends and family. Those of us who were more in tune with how to operate and culture friendships strictly online, watched in glee as our new e-friends started adding us on Facebook, Twitter, and Discord. There had been countless memes already at the beginning of quarantine. The introverts, as we had been so aptly named, had been preparing for this apocalypse all our lives. Our stockpiles of memes and screenshots taking up our phones' memory, and yet weighing nothing on our shoulders. </p>

<p>But to others, the world had stopped turning. To the introvert, those missed encounters don't mean much. But, to that one very social friend, they lost their outlet. Humans are social, we need to be building and maintaining relationships to survive. "Just do it over FaceBook." That is what many people would think. </p>

<p>Take a moment and think back to the early days, when MySpace was huge, and FaceBook had just started. There was this craze of adding as many people as you could, if you sat next to them on the bus once, they might end up as your friend. Then, suddenly the brakes on that metaphorical bus were slammed. Everyone began to preach for privacy, which in reality never existed. </p>

<p>All the while, the digital generation forming anonymous communities in forums and threads using synonyms. Never knowing Sk8trBoi10's face didn't matter, because, to us, they were our teammate, our clanmate, our friend. </p>

<p>That's where we were before this pandemic, the necessity for that face-to-face element being the core aspect of forging a friendship, at least normally. </p>

<p>Although it was slow, the people that didn't know how to socialize online have adapted. They miss what they had, but they hopefully learn to focus on what they do have. What they do have is social media. It's time to stop acting like social media doesn't play a key role in our lives. </p>

<p>What skills can we instill then into these people, for them to use their social media to the fullest of its capabilities? </p>

<p>People will be able to create and maintain a presence on social media for personal and professional purposes. If that is what they want. (Some are content remaining unplugged, and that is okay.)  </p>

<p>This education would include learning how to separate their social media into spheres of focus. Not physical spheres, but digital. They know what type of audience could be seeing their posts, and how to manage that information. If you enjoy sharing some really over the top memes, don't worry you will still be able to do that. They can communicate well, without anger, but with empathy, while evaluating interaction online, and have nurtured a healthy digital environment for themselves.</p>

<p>The first sphere of focus is the mental and emotional sphere.  When you can't go running to your best friend's house, and collapse face down on their bed in tears, because 'Rona, students will know the alternative. Have spent time creating a personal space where they are able to speak freely, with those they know can communicate openly with them. </p>

<p>The second sphere covers friendships and communication. How to communicate with empathy, and understand what is needed and being asked by someone else. Even if the student themselves doesn't have the answer, the ability to simply understand what someone else is in need of is a skill that has been lost.</p>

<p>The third sphere of focus is the consumer sphere. This covers dealing with ads, to impulse buying, to the distribution and creation of memes.  </p>

<p>The fourth sphere covers professionalism, and how to create accounts on platforms for the use of getting yourself noticed by possible employers. Including how to still operate as a top-level FaceBook MemeLord, and still let employers click on your FaceBook.</p>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Created a new page on my personal website for my learning log.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Log]]></description><link>https://madisynbenge.wixsite.com/mysite/post/created-a-new-page-on-my-personal-website-for-my-learning-log</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5f4c44dcda01970017004ba5</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:31:42 GMT</pubDate><dc:creator>Madisyn Benge</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Log</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>